Guide to the Morse Hardware Company records 1891-1999
Western Washington University, Center for Pacific Northwest Studies
- Morse Hardware Company, 1884-1994; Series I
  - Subject Files, 1890-1994; Sub-series 6
    - Letters of Interest, 1959-1984 (Box-folder 10/13)
    - Letters- Humorous from Alaska and Others, 1971-1994 (Box-folder 10/14)
    - Letterheads- Local Businesses, 1894-1938 (Box-folder 10/15)
    - Letterheads- Vendors, 1893-1925 (Box-folder 10/16)
    - Letterheads and Invoices- Morse Hardware, 1890-1946 (Box-folder 10/17)
    - National Wholesale Hardware Association- Bob Morse, 1986-1991 (Box-folder 10/18)
    - News Clippings- Morse Hardware Company, 1905-1979 (Box-folder 10/19)
    - News Clippings- Morse Hardware Company, 1937-1984 (Box-folder 10/20)
    - News Clippings- from Cecil Morse Files, 1901-1962 (Box-folder 10/21)
    - Newspaper- Puget Sound Mail, Thursday October 29, 1942 (Box-folder 10/22)
    - Photographs and Pictures, Pre-1950 (Box-folder 10/23)
    - Photographs and Pictures, Post-1950 (Box-folder 10/24)
    - Postcards and Salesmen Call Cards, 1895-1948 (Box-folder 10/25)
    - Press Kit- Boise Cascade, 1968 (Box-folder 10/26)
    - Press Kit- Pechiney Enterprises (Franco-American Aluminum Mill, Bellingham), 1965 (Box-folder 10/27)
    - PRO Hardware Incorporated (Includes photographs), 1966-1988 (Box-folder 10/28)
    - San Juan Islands, 1925-1929 (Box-folder 11/1)
    - Scrapbook, 1903-1918 (Box-folder 11/2)
    - Shipping Labels, Undated (Box-folder 11/3)
    - Stock Certificates- County Fair, 1919-1928 (Box-folder 11/4)
    - Stock Certificates- Mining Companies, Undated (Box-folder 11/5)
    - Vouchers- Bellingham Bay Gas Company, 1899-1900 (Box-folder 11/6)
    - Washington State Register of Historic Places- Morse Hardware Company Building- Plaque Design, 1984 (Box-folder 11/7)
- Morse Family Materials, 1886-1999; Series II
  - Cecil A. Morse files, 1906-1959 (Box-folder 11/8)
  - Cecil A. Morse files, 1916-1952 (Box-folder 11/9)
  - Cecil A. Morse Genealogy Material, 1943 (Box-folder 11/10)
  - Cecil A. Morse – Mining Interest, 1928-1941 (Box-folder 11/11)
  - Cecil A. Morse- Stock Certificates
    - Stock Certificates, 1903-1942 (Box-folder 11/12)
    - Stock Certificates, 1907-1960 (Box-folder 11/13)
    - Stock Certificates, 1920-1930 (Box-folder 11/14)
    - Stock Certificates, 1920-1936 (Box-folder 11/15)
  - David C. Morse files, 1928-1992 (Box-folder 11/16)
  - David C. Morse- Chi Psi Fraternity-“The Purple and Gold”, Spring 1970 (Box-folder 11/17)
  - David C. Morse- Stamp and Envelope Collection, 1933-1981 (Box-folder 11/18)
  - R.I. Morse- Company History and Biographical Information, 1887-1989 (Box-folder 11/19)
  - R.I. Morse- Condolence Letters, 1920 (Box-folder 11/20)
  - R.I. Morse- Obituary, April 1920 (Box-folder 11/21)
  - R.I. Morse- National Register of Historic Houses- 1014 Garden Street Residence (includes original deed), 1886-1971 (Box-folder 11/22)
  - Robert (Bob) Morse, 1980-1994 (Box-folder 11/23)
- Bellingham and Whatcom County History, 1883-1992; Series III
  - Blueprints: Hannegan's Tide corner of West Holly and E Streets, undated (Box-folder 12/1)
  - Chamber of Commerce- Ferry Committee, 1937-1958 (Box-folder 12/2)
  - Chamber of Commerce- Misc. (Box-folder 12/3)
  - Chamber of Commerce- Special Committees, 1919-1955 (Box-folder 12/4)
  - Events and Activities
    - Lincoln Assassination - reported in the New York Herald, April 15, 1965 (Box-folder 12/5)
    - Mt. Baker Lodge brochure, Undated (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Mt. Baker Theatre Opening Program, 1927 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Tulip Festival, 1923 (Box-folder 12/6)
    - Manuscript: “I Found It! A History of Early Whatcom County Bottles” Revised Edition by David Bethman, 1988 (Box-folder 12/7)
    - Manuscript: “Whatcom County Post Offices and Postmasters 1857-1985”, 1986 (Box-folder 12/8)
    - News Clippings- Local History, 1889-1990 (Box-folder 12/9)
    - The Northwest Magazine: Bellingham Bay (Incomplete), September 1889 (Box-folder 12/10)
  - Pacific American Fisheries, 1901-1965 (Box-folder 12/11)
  - Pamphlets Relating to Bellingham and Whatcom County: “History of Bellingham Y.M.C.A. 1890-1962” (Box-folder 12/12)
  - “An Introduction to the Economy of Whatcom County”, 1977 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - “Mt. Baker Ski Area- A Pictorial History”, 1980 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - “Bellingham: The Town of the Month”, April 1929 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - “Whatcom Museum, An Official Guide”, 1992 (Box-folder 12/12)
  - Periodicals
    - “Business Pulse”, September 1989 (Box-folder 12/13)
    - “Pacific Fisherman Handbook", May 1944 (Box-folder 12/14)
    - “Pacific Fisherman's Salmon Canners Directory”, 1917; 1918 (Box-folder 12/15)
    - “Salmon Packers Directory” published by Pacific Fisherman, 1919 (Box-folder 12/16)
    - “Salmon Packers Register” published by Pacific Fisherman, 1920; 1922; 1923; 1929; 1931; 1934-1935; 1937; 1945; 1948-1949; 1953; 1956; 1959 (Box-folder 12/17)
  - Port of Bellingham- Agreements, Information, and Statistics, 1929-1948 (Box-folder 12/18)
  - Port of Bellingham- “Port Reports”, October and December 1988; October and November 1989 (Box-folder 12/19)
  - Salmon Can Labels, Undated (Box-folder 12/20)
  - Talks- Historical by David C. Morse, 1984-1990 (Box-folder 12/21)
  - Telephone subscribers, 1890 (Box-folder 12/22)
  - Reunions, 1925-1931 (Box-folder 12/23)
  - Thank-you letters from Parkview School for Playground Equipment Donation, 1972 (Box-folder 12/23)
  - Whatcom County School Directory, 1922 (Box-folder 12/24)
  - Oversize Maps of Bellingham and Surrounding Area
    - Aeroview of Whatcom County Washington, 1930 (Box-folder 13/1)
    - Baker View Addition plat map, 1938 (Box-folder 13/2)
    - Baker View Addition showing Morse Hardware tracts, Undated (Box-folder 13/3)
    - Bellingham Bay Coal Company property with the town of Sehome and the adjoining towns of Whatcom and Bellingham in the County of Whatcom, July 1883 (Box-folder 13/4)
    - Commercial map of Bellingham, Washington, 1926 (Box-folder 13/5)
    - Enlarged portion of plat of portion of Sehome – Laurell St. and Railroad Avenue, Undated (Box-folder 13/6)
    - Map & Elevations: Morse Hardware Tract, February 15, 1940 (Box-folder 13/7)
    - Plat of Bellingham Bay Coal Company’s Properties in Sehome, 1883 (Box-folder 13/8)
  - Polk Directories
    - Puget Sound Directory, 1887 (Box-folder 14/1)
    - New Whatcom, 1891 (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Oregon, Washington, Idaho Gazetteer, 1892 (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Oregon, Washington, and Alaska, 1901 (Box-folder 15/1)
    - Oregon, Washington, and Alaska, 1902 (Box-folder 15/2)
    - Oregon and Washington Gazetteer, 1903 (Box-folder 15/3)
    - Oregon and Washington Gazetteer, 1904 (Box-folder 15/4)
    - Oregon and Washington Gazetteer, 1905 (Box-folder 15/5)
    - Oregon and Washington Gazetteer, 1906 (Box-folder 15/6)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1917 (Box-folder 15/7)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1925 (Box-folder 15/8)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County (2nd Copy), 1925 (Box-folder 15/9)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1926 (Box-folder 15/10)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County (2nd Copy), 1926 (Box-folder 15/11)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County (3rd Copy), 1926 (Box-folder 15/12)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1927 (Box-folder 15/13)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County (2nd Copy), 1927 (Box-folder 15/14)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1928 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1929 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County (2nd Copy), 1929 (Box-folder 16/3)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1930 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County (2nd Copy), 1930 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1931 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1932 (Box-folder 16/7)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County (2nd Copy), 1932 (Box-folder 16/8)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1933 (Box-folder 16/9)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1934 (Box-folder 16/10)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1935 (Box-folder 16/11)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1936 (Box-folder 16/12)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County (2nd Copy), 1936 (Box-folder 16/13)
    - Bellingham and Whatcom County, 1937 (Box-folder 16/14)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1939 (Box-folder 17/1)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1940 (Box-folder 17/2)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1941 (Box-folder 17/3)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1942 (Box-folder 17/4)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1945 (Box-folder 17/5)
    - Bellingham City Directories (2nd Copy), 1945 (Box-folder 17/6)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1947 (Box-folder 17/7)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1948 (Box-folder 17/8)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1950 (Box-folder 17/9)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1952 (Box-folder 17/10)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1954 (Box-folder 18/1)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1955 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1956 (Box-folder 18/3)
    - Bellingham City Directories (2nd Copy), 1956 (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1957 (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Bellingham City Directories (2nd Copy), 1957 (Box-folder 18/6)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1959 (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1960 (Box-folder 18/8)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1961 (Box-folder 18/9)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1964 (Box-folder 18/10)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1966 (Box-folder 19/1)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1967 (Box-folder 19/2)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1968 (Box-folder 19/3)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1969 (Box-folder 19/4)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1970 (Box-folder 19/5)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1971 (Box-folder 19/6)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1972 (Box-folder 19/7)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1973 (Box-folder 19/8)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1974 (Box-folder 19/9)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1975 (Box-folder 20/1)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1976 (Box-folder 20/2)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1977 (Box-folder 20/3)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1978 (Box-folder 20/4)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1979 (Box-folder 20/5)
    - Bellingham City Directories, 1980 (Box-folder 20/6)
  - Artifacts from Cecil Morse's Desk
    - Address Book, 1945 (Box-folder 21/1)
    - Diaries, 1900-1955 (Box-folder 21/2)
    - Maps and Travel Guides
      - Bellingham and Whatcom County, circa 1920-1950 (Box-folder 21/3)
      - Europe, 1925-1949 (Box-folder 21/4)
      - North America, circa 1929-1940 (Box-folder 21/5)
      - North America, circa 1920-1940 (Box-folder 21/6)
      - North America, circa 1920-1960 (Box-folder 21/7)
      - North America, circa 1920-1960 (Box-folder 22/1)
      - North America, circa 1920-1960 (Box-folder 22/2)
      - Washington State, 1925 (Box-folder 22/3)
      - Washington State, circa 1920-1960 (Box-folder 22/4)
      - Washington State, circa 1920-1960 (Box-folder 22/5)
    - Time Book – personal employees, 1938-1939 (Box-folder 22/6)
    - Ready reference materials (tool and equipment guides, business practices, conversion tables), 1899-1950s (Box 23)
    - The Great American Hardware Story Vol. 212 No. 7 Morse Hardware Advertisement, July 4, 1975 (Box 23)
    - Hardware Merchandiser, October 1987 (Box 23)
    - Hardware Merchandiser, “Hardware Merchandisers of the Year: David C. Morse” + Extra Copies of the Cover, October 1969 (Box 23)
    - Morse Hardware Advertisement, undated (Box 23)
    - Tickets and fliers for social events, circa 1920-1960 (Box 24)
    - Stamps (Morse Hardware and Cecil Morse), Undated (Box 24)
    - Desk items – letter opener, pencil lead, paperweight, Undated (Box 24)
    - “Coolidge and Dawes” campaign buttons, Undated (Box 24)
    - Labeled keys to various areas of the Hardware Store, Undated (Box 24)